Recording has started and I'm admitting
everybody into the meeting.
So as people are coming on in.
Good morning, everybody.
This is Dominic Zerlow.
I'm the Director for the Center for
Medical Cannabis and Psilocybin.
Welcome to this morning's meeting for the
Research and Continuous Improvement
Committee for the Medical Psilocybin
Advisory Board with Dan Jennings as chair.
Just as a couple of housekeeping
reminders,
we do have cameras off for the majority
of people that are on here so that we can
ensure that there is enough bandwidth for
most people and that they don't keep
dropping on and off.
We are having some Internet issues in one
of our locations at the Department of
Health, so you will see,
you will not see the Department of Health
staff unless they are speaking again to
help keep with that bandwidth.
We do have some guest speakers today when
those speakers are elevated to be
presenters, just to let you know,
if you would like to turn your cameras on,
you will be able to do so.
I'll remind people at that point when,
when that portion,
those portions start and at this time,
I will turn it on over to you, Dan.
Or would you like me to just go right
into updates?
Well,
actually what I was going to say is I was
going to say, well,
thank everybody to come here.
But then I was going to turn it right
back over to you and say,
please introduce your team and any kind
of updates from.
So yeah, we're you.
You're reading my mind.
OK, well, thank you, Dan.
So today from Department of Health,
we have,
and I'm just going to go in listed order.
We have some of our health educators,
Carmen Bautista, Adrian Estrada,
and Ishmael Zutat.
We also have our medical director,
Doctor Robert Truckner.
We have some of our support staff as well,
who actually is the one who helps us and
takes care of all things regarding these
meetings, Johnny Moshe.
And from the psilocybin program,
we have the program manager,
Jorge Gonzalez and we let me see who else
we have.
Oh,
we also have Leslie Peterson and Cyrus
Rautman,
who are both with our psilocybin team.
And then we also have our Deputy Director,
Brenda Martinez here on the line.
If I've missed any of our staff,
I apologize and you can put that on into
the chat if I did miss someone.
And then as far as updates,
so a couple of things that some of the
big items that are of course happening
are that we do have the first set of
rules which will be coming on up for the
rule hearing, which is set for April 24th.
And I'll put that in the chat in just a
moment.
The information for that.
And if you want to read through those,
those rules, you are able to do so.
You just can go to the website and read
them.
And then there's instructions there on
how, if you have public comment,
how to submit public comment.
Just as a note,
during any of the committee meetings in
the Advisory Board,
comments that are made there are not
considered a part of public comment for
rule hearings.
It must go to the e-mail address that is
listed in the announcement for it to be
part of that public record.
So just to let everyone know,
you can still make comments to us.
For example,
we have a propagation meeting that is
next Wednesday.
So if you're interested in that,
since these rules cover and look at
cultivation and testing,
you're welcome come to that and express
thoughts and opinions,
but they are not a part of that public
record for the rulemaking.
So if you have something specific for
that,
please make sure to send it in through
e-mail to the e-mail address.
It is different than the usual medical
dot psilocybin.
So look in the notice to make sure that
you have the correct e-mail that goes
actually to our legal team and they're
the ones who have to compile that.
So, so we do have that coming up.
And again,
I'll put that into the chat in a minute.
I have already put into the chat the list
of all the other meetings that are coming
up over the next, oh,
a little more than a month going all the
way through to May 15th as of right now.
And so those were all there including
training and education.
That's this afternoon.
There is a hybrid meeting for end of life
care Thursday the 28th, 23rd.
There is also a hybrid meeting for the
equity access and cultural consideration
on the 28th.
And so the information for that is also
on the program website and that is also
in the chat right now.
So if you want to go and check on those,
Please remember to register for those
different meetings just so that we have
that list and we welcome everybody to
attend.
Other than that,
I think those are the main aspects that
we have going on right now.
So I'll turn it back on over to you, Dan,
and thank you very much for the few
minutes to provide announcements.
Perfect.
Thank you very much, Ali.
Appreciate that and welcome everybody for
coming to our meeting today.
And I'm going to give you just a
highlight of our kind of four beats that
we'll have today.
So within this 20 minutes that we're
starting the meeting with this is all the
introductions and the welcome and such.
So to prepare y'all for this next part,
I would love for y'all to introduce
yourselves.
And to do that, just raise your hand,
just use that raise hand button that's up
there at the top of your teams meeting
page and you can get in queue.
So we would love to hear from you a
little bit about yourself.
So we've got about one minute per
introduction.
Just say who you are.
I would love to know your affiliations
and if this is the first time for you
attending this meeting or if you're
returning, if you go to other meetings,
just let us know.
We would just love to know a little bit
more about you.
So please go ahead and get in line and
start raising your hands and we'll do
that for the next probably till 922.
So OK, I'll start at the top.
There we have Doctor Lydia Fatemi.
If I believe I've enabled your mic,
please begin when ready.
Hi, I'm Doctor Lita Fatemi,
I'm the founder of the Conscious
Physician Psychedelics Academy.
That's a local Academy educating
healthcare providers in utilization of
psilocybin.
And I'm also a Hospice physician with ABQ
Hospice and Palliative.
Thank you so much for having us here.
Next we have Kate Hawk.
Kate, I have enabled your mic.
Please begin when ready.
Good morning, everyone.
This is Kate Hawk.
Probably know most of you,
but for this meeting,
I'll just say I'm have 40 years as a
trauma therapist,
longer than that with psychedelics.
And next week,
I'm going to be working with Sue Sicily
on the Scottsdale Research Institute with
a group of 8 veterans in their FDA phase
one study.
And, you know,
happy to be here as New Mexico develops
such a system that we can be a model.
Thank you.
Next we have Hannah Rose.
I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
Hi, Good morning.
My name is Hanna Rose.
I'm a BSW student here in Silver City,
New New Mexico.
I'm learning about social work and I'm
also affiliated with the Heart of Earth
and Sky Sanctuary.
It's where I've had my some of my
psychedelic training with.
Yeah,
I've been working with psilocybin for
over 20 years,
and I'm just very excited to be a part of
this beautiful program and see the faces
and hands and hearts showing up.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Next we have Sam Wolfe.
Sam, I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
Good morning, Sam Wolfe.
I'm an attorney here in Santa Fe with a
personal and professional interest in
knowing how the rules are developing.
Thank you.
Thank you very much for that.
Next we have Caroline Kroland.
Caroline, please begin.
When ready,
I have enabled your microphone and
Caroline,
just to let you know there to enable your
microphone on your end,
you have to click on the mic icon that's
located on the top right of your
Microsoft Teams application.
If that is not working,
you can always drop off the call and
maybe join back in.
That often does help,
but you can also check if your microphone
is enabled by clicking on the little
downward arrow located on the right hand
side of your microphone just to specify
to the computer or to the application
which where your microphone is coming
from.
But I will give it a few more seconds and
then what I will do is I'll kindly move
on to James Brown.
OK,
We're going to move over to James Brown
now.
I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks Dan again for sharing this.
My name is James Brown.
I'm a doctor of pharmacy here in New
Mexico.
I'm a Navy veteran.
I'm very passionate about psychedelics.
I'm a psychedelic certified facilitator.
I'm representing 5° N Healing Foundation,
which is a nonprofit for first responders
and veterans with PTSD and other type of
issues.
Thank you so much.
Thank you very much for that.
And before I continue,
there's just something in the chat there,
Kathy Sanchez,
Bureau Chief of for Workers Compensation
Administration, medical cost containment.
So thank you very much for that.
Catherine.
Next we have Gregory Evans there.
I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin, of course, when ready.
Good morning.
My name is Gregory Evans.
I'm an independent researcher and home
psychologist with no affiliations.
I'm a Santa Fe resident and my intention
is to support programs development
through committee recommendations aligned
with emerging research and best practices.
Thank you very much for that, Gregory.
Next we have Elaine Brewer.
I believe I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
Hi everyone.
It's great to see you all this morning.
I'm Eileen Brewer.
I am affiliated with Cluster Buster's.
I'm an expert in pain and psychedelics,
and I've been working on patient
education in this space for a dozen years
or more.
Glad to be here.
It's a pleasure to have you here.
Next, we have Brenda Burgard.
Brenda, I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks for having me here today.
I really appreciate all of what we're
doing here today.
I am chairing the training and education
for the medical psilocybin this afternoon
from 1:00 to 3:00.
And I'm so happy to be here to join with
everybody to really forge ahead and see
what we can do to make this wonderful
thing happen for New Mexico.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much for that and
appreciate that.
Next we have before I go on to enable
other people's mics,
we just have something in the chat there.
Mary Hofstadt, I believe a good morning.
Mary Hofstadt,
Santa Fe based program director for the
Modern Elder Academy, glad to be here.
Thank you very much for that, Mary.
Next we have Danielle Leonard.
Danielle, I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
And just as an additional reminder,
if you want to unmute yourself,
you have to do so on the top right using
the microphone icon.
So just have to click that button.
If that is not working,
perhaps maybe check on the right hand
side,
there's a downwards arrow just to make
sure that you have the correct microphone
attributed.
And if that's not working,
simply drop off the call and then attempt
to maybe join back.
In the meantime,
we're going to jump over to James Ferrari.
I believe I have enabled your microphone.
Please do go ahead.
Hey everybody, James Ferrara,
I'm affiliated with Ignite Synergy.
We have a a psychedelic EHR that we hope
will help drive this market.
I'm also Albuquerque been here for a very
long time.
So good to see you.
All pleasure.
Thank you very much for that.
And I'm just gonna go back,
right back to Danielle just one more time.
Daniel,
if you can hear us just drop a little
line in the chat,
perhaps that may be that we have
something there in the chat.
Let's just take a look there.
Good morning.
Sorry I can't seem to unmute.
I'm a therapist based in Santa Fe.
I'm also researching with NMHU.
Thank you very much for that, Danielle.
Next we have Caroline Crowland.
Welcome back.
I have enabled your microphone.
Please go ahead when ready.
Still seem to have a few issues there.
Caroline, if you just.
Yeah, like I said,
on the microphone application,
on the microphone icon located on the top
right of the Microsoft Teams app,
you should see a downwards arrow really
quite close on the right hand side next
to the microphone icon.
Just click that just to see if you are
again utilizing the correct microphone.
And if that's not working,
please do present your information and
introduce yourself in the chat and we
will read that out accordingly.
Finally though, we have Desba.
Desba, I have enabled your microphone.
Please begin when ready.
Yat a this is Desba.
I am Chair of the Equity Access and
Cultural Committee Committee,
cultural considerations committee.
Just saying hi,
just here to hear what's the conversation.
Good morning, everyone.
Thank you very much for that.
And we have a comment in the chat just by
by by Lydia, who was the member with EHR.
I don't quite recall.
I think that was James Ferreira.
James, there we go.
Thank you very much.
All done, John.
Dan, you have better memory than I do.
That's OK.
I've been doing,
I've been I've been trying to study
everything every time Y'all have the
meeting so incredible.
Well, I pass over to yourself then.
In any case,
that seems to be everyone's introductions
done.
So I humbly pass back over to yourself.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it.
And I saw that we have Tiffany Scott in
the chat too.
Good morning, everyone.
So appreciate you being here.
And then we got a few more people that
just came in.
So thank you very much for putting into
the chat box.
We've got Ben from norrishcap.com,
the platform where all things mushrooms
and Carolyn Prolin, very good.
Thanks for putting in the chat.
Carolyn Prolin, I'm with Fireside Project,
it's my first meeting Pleasure to be here
and I'm really glad that you're here from
Fireside Project.
So thanks for joining us here and please
hope you know everybody.
The chat box has like some of the other
meetings that are coming up.
We're in this meetings later on today for
education and training.
So don't forget, if you can,
and come to some of those other trainings,
some of those other committee hearings
and board meetings as well.
Please.
Really appreciate that.
So again,
just to kind of go over some of the beats
that we'll have today,
this is our 1st 20 minutes.
So the introduction, welcome and framing.
And we're about to move into our next
large part,
which is about 60 minute block where
we'll talk about intersectional work
presentations and discussions.
So if you remember from our previous
meeting that we had last month,
we had three working groups that we're
working outside of the committee meetings
that we're having here to report back to
us on three different things,
challenging and adverse experiences,
emergency preparedness and patient
community education.
So we'll start those in just a little bit
just to let everybody kind of know how
we'll handle those is it'll be about a 10
minute block of presentation for each one
of those and between each one we'll also
have a 10 minute discussion period.
During that time,
I would appreciate if you would use your
chat box in order to ask any questions or
to prepare.
You know,
if even if you come across I'm like, yes,
that's fantastic, drop that in there too.
Whatever feedback you would like,
we would like if there is any kind of
questions, you have to drop them in.
And during that next 10 minutes then the
team will be able to to talk about that.
No decisions are being made here.
Don't forget this is simply just
presentation.
The idea is for everybody to hear and
then to see some of these concepts and
then to walk away from this meeting so
that in our main meeting we'll be able to
have deeper discussions about them.
So again,
don't take this as this is the way that
things are going to be.
It is simply the presentation.
So I just wanted to set like level set
everybody on that and remember
everybody's norms again,
is that think large,
but act minimally and don't use
assumptions.
Just ask any questions that you might
have.
Everybody has equal voice in this at this
time.
So just really wanted to make everybody
aware of that and be sure I'm always
going to say this as well, but you know,
point your things at the at the at the
information and not to the people.
So I'll just leave that out there as well.
Then in our next 25 minutes after that,
we're going to start talking about
convergence and next steps.
So what are recommendations that we can
give to each one of those work groups for
the topics?
We'll have owners of that work, of course.
And if there's anything that comes up in
the chat that might be parking lot issues,
we'll put those over there because it
doesn't mean we're ignoring them.
It just means it may not pertain to one
of these three items at the moment,
but we'll still put that up there.
And I want you to kind of share some of
the blind spots that we're missing,
some things that we're not aware of that
we need to be thinking about and,
and that could kind of help set our next
May meeting as well.
So I would love to hear all of those
kinds of things during this meeting.
And then we'll be able to enter in that
time,
kind of open up microphones and talk
about it and then we'll finish up with
public comment and close up in that last
few minutes that we have about 15 minutes.
That's kind of the beats we have right
now.
We're going to move into the
intersectional work discussion and we
have three groups.
The first one is being led by James Brown.
I believe that James Brown.
You also have Gregory Evans and Danielle
Leonard with you on that.
So I'm just giving the heads up to the
team to allow for their microphones and
you can turn your cameras on if you'd
like and then also share anything.
And I will begin the 10 minutes.
Like I said,
I'm a taskmaster so I have a 10 minute
timer going whenever you are ready.
James, you,
Greg and Danielle are all elevated
presenters.
So if you also want to show yourself or
share screen for any items,
you are able to do so and you can mute
and unmute yourselves that.
Well.
Thank you so much, Dominique and Dan,
we're going to have Gregory present and
we will do the discussions.
And again,
thank you so much to this amazing team
with Gregory Evans and Danielle Leonard.
Those are the two that were part of this
group.
And again, they're so amazing.
So we really want to start off the the
this discussion and then let you guys
know what this group is that their
definitions is.
There's two big definitions here for
everybody.
The big takeaways here were the
definitions of what's a challenging event
and then also what's an adverse event.
I think that's really big for the group
to understand and distinguish.
Let's start with challenging event.
A challenging event is difficult in a
session moment when when your patient or
or the person you're you're therapy with
is,
is having a difficult session a
challenging moment?
Again,
it should be defined and that's what
we're saying here is,
is this is for discussion.
A difficult in the session moment often
therapeutically productive,
but it's distinguished by absence of
objective harm.
And then what is an adverse event?
We were saying that adverse event
definition would be an outcome involving
measurable clinical pathology and again
that would be with objective harm.
And so a challenging event could be fear,
grief, anxiety, confusion, side effects,
nausea, vomiting,
other things like that could be
challenging in the moment versus adverse
events.
An adverse event could be something that
is a cardiac event, a serotonin syndrome,
which is very rare,
maybe an HPBD very rare again,
or a psychotic break.
Those would be adverse events.
And so that's what we wanted to kind of
do.
Gregory, your thoughts on this?
Yeah,
just really quick as as we walk into this
conversation,
I have all of our slides prepared as
publicly accessible links.
Is it OK if I drop those in the chat?
Yes, go ahead.
I don't know if you heard me, but yes,
go ahead.
Yeah, sorry, just making sure,
just getting rid of some linked garbage.
But basically there's three links here.
We're going to go over what we just
discussed,
the introduction of challenging versus
adverse, right?
And clarifying that language,
which is super important.
And we're discussing the topic of
measuring and tracking adverse events.
So with each of these links,
if anyone wants to go into those and
follow along, they can.
If they want to comment you any,
everyone should have the ability to
comment directly on those links as well
as comment in the chat.
Well,
I'm just going to kind of burn through
this because we are on a clock.
My little taskmaster there is nodding his
head with joy.
Absolutely love seeing that this morning.
And James just button if, if, if you need,
if you need to cover something on this
page, we cover our key terms.
We also cover some of the deviations that
our group came up with that will differ
from the current most recent version of
recommendations.
And we have justifications further down
and you can explore these tiered
instruments,
but basically we have universal
instruments,
pathway specific instruments and then
clinician administered instruments.
And the reason that matters to us is we
find ourselves all the way down here in
the safety and adverse events instruments
and defining those and the parameters
around those is something we wanted to do
today.
There's another call out that I wanted to
actually hand this over to to James to
discuss the,
I just wanted to address the complex PTSD.
Do you want to talk about that for about
30 seconds?
Yeah.
What we tried to do, everyone is,
is as you go through the different ICD
TIN coding and the different disease
state and the different things that we're
going to have to address,
a lot of these adverse events were preset
by,
if we look at the model that's already
out there, if we look at Colorado,
we look at Oregon,
we say what's out there already?
What can we extrapolate and what can we
look at what clinical articles were out
there that was really big.
Is that what we went out there and said?
What else is out there?
And we found a great article by Polinski
that we wanted to share with everybody
that Danielle found for us.
Again, thank you,
Danielle so much and so important on that.
But with PTSDI,
think it's important that the complexity,
everybody knows that these are very
complex patients and that it's very
important that we handle these adverse
events appropriately or within less harm,
right?
So we want to do harm reduction with
these type of complex trauma based
patients, you know,
they can have very prolonged dopaminergic
type of receptor issues.
And and So what we'd like to do is just
recognize that that that is something
that is different than maybe, you know,
end of life therapy,
that that's different than substance use
disorder,
that each one of these adverse or
challenging events should be sub
categorized into each, you know,
each thing.
And so each disease state or each thing
that we're treating, Yeah.
And on that, yeah.
And on that point,
like what we're looking at is taking all
of the measurements and categorizing them
and,
and pointing out that adverse events is
definitely down here.
The program will be monitoring all of
these things and everything is connected.
And I just wanted everybody to have a
chance to go through this.
Throw comments in here, come back later.
At the bottom of this page,
you'll find a categorized measurements,
the clinical instruments in their
categories and the specific instrument
instruments that we currently have
available in our recommendation that fall
under those hoods, you know, and that way,
hopefully the massive dump of 20
instruments doesn't feel as daunting.
But to try to bring it home in our last
minute,
if we can go over for a little bit,
this is kind of a major,
major thing that we're coming with today.
As far as recommendation in the world of
adverse events, this is very wordy,
so I'll try to like just skim through it.
But in the world of adverse events,
there is not a tool that works for this
type of experience.
There is a group at Emory University who
in 2004 published,
I would almost call it a beta version of
what is called the PATAE.
And what this instrument does,
is it like what their what their what
their research paper did was took every
existing battery that covered adverse
events and they pulled what was useful
for psychedelic therapy and built a model
A built in instrument from that review.
They call it V Thank you.
Thank you.
They call it V 0.1, right.
And it definitely needs some work.
We have a domain coverage gap analysis on
that instrument here.
And what this shows us is where our
department could make it better for us
based on what it has, what it's capturing,
how it's administered,
and what is missing for our needs.
This is something that I'm looking
forward to a lot of people like
commenting on and and providing input.
Input, as Gregory's saying here,
this is this was the framework that
Polinski proposed.
Again, that's New Mexicans.
We want to come up with our own framework,
right.
So what we were trying to do with you
guys is get you information out there
that's a framework basis and then we can
modify that, come up with new things,
take whatever we want to do to make our
own New Mexican framework.
So that's kind of the thought behind some
of this is they use the of wide variety
of batteries, great instruments.
And so we can take a lot of these things
that are out there and say what's really
going to count for what disease state and
what's going to be important.
And Gregory's kind of formatted as we'll
show you here in a little while,
which one is what.
And just to give you ideas,
this is our ideas for thoughts.
There's that preparation area,
dosing session integration and then this
great thing called follow up.
So there,
that's kind of some of the areas that we
were discussing too.
Just because we have 00 minutes,
I just want to point out to everyone,
if you click on these links,
they will take you to the actual research
papers that went into the the Politsky's
work.
And what we want to recommend to the
department officially is that we reach
out for a partnership with the domain and
help them bring PATAE home by giving it
government regulated program.
I think it's a win win.
And that's a much bigger discussion than
we have time here for today.
But yes, everyone,
please enjoy my nerd collections and have
a good day.
Thank you both.
I really appreciate it again.
And all three of you appreciate y'all
being part of this.
I'm not going to take a lot of time to,
to celebrate of that because I don't want
to take away from the comments,
but I did have to make that comment.
It's huge, It's fantastic.
Thank you for putting this body of work
in front of everybody.
I think it's huge again, in the comments,
please leave comments again,
like I know it's going to be a lot for
you to have to read and and digest,
but it's very critical for us to do so
because at our main meeting,
we can really have some,
some true consensus at that point to move
forward with while we do some of the
background work intersessionally.
Ben, per adverse event,
are there any words to characterize the
come in addition to the existence of such
events in other areas of the country,
people are assuming the worst from these
hospitalizations even when in fact there
have been positive outcome following
without additional words or tracking such
events could lead to an unruly naive
characterization.
Yes,
The idea that we have published
originally was the CATAE which of course
is based on oncology and it is anything
from from some mildly upsetting events
all the way to very adverse events.
But the PATAE as proposed here is a
fantastic model off of the CATAE that
then does in my opinion,
what you're talking about is that it
characterizes between challenging that
could be healing and growth all the way
to adverse,
which is where we really need to look at
session issue yet whatever might happen
to come in there.
So unless anybody want to add and Brenda,
thank you vital for education and
training.
Great work.
So great.
You can kind of take this on to your your
next meeting as well.
I'm going to let anybody else put
comments in,
but I'll let Gregory and James in the
meantime,
if you wanted to address anything that
Ben had put in there,
maybe what I explained was perfect.
I'm I'm going to kind of leave it.
I think it is.
OK.
And one last thing for everybody just
real quick is again,
challenging events is something that
we're going to see most likely all the
time as a facilitator.
And that's what we want to see.
We want to see these people have
challenging events.
This is where they grow.
This is where they get better.
And then versus adverse events,
I think this is going to be rarities.
They are very serious,
but they're rarities and they're in,
I'm not saying the one offs,
but when they do happen,
we just need to have that, that pathway,
that funneling and then the data to make
sure we collect all that so we can
improve.
And I wanted to piggyback on that as well
is that before there really wasn't a lot
of,
we've been trying to find
instrumentalities that would help really
define that objectively instead of just
subjectively.
And I really have to say that you all on
your team have come up with some
wonderful tested,
evaluated and and accepted protocols for
that.
And I know that they didn't get because
of the 10 minute timer that I am such the
taskmaster of.
This is the reason why it is critical for
you to use that link that is there to
look at this information because I know
that some from our previous meeting was
like that's a lot of things to do and a
lot of time.
And I have to say that this team has come
up with timing protocols on this and it's
split between in session,
out of session and patient.
So therefore the time requirements,
the administrative overhead is not as
great.
But again,
please look at those protocols and see
how it can help with all four parts of
the session and all four domains of these
kind of adverse slash challenging
experiences.
So, Danielle, one way to look at it is,
is an adverse event requires an
intervention and a challenging event does
not.
And the intervention is very is, is, is,
is a continuum as well.
What is the intervention?
Is it a first response?
Is it a hospitalization?
Is it long term?
So therefore, you're exactly right.
We still have about 5 minutes of this
discussion.
I'm, I'm filling the gap of time.
So please just continue then.
Then then could a hospitalization be
categorized as a level lower than adverse,
like challenging or would it always be
adverse?
The hospitalization,
the actual outcome of it is not
necessarily what defines in all ways.
There are some in the PATAE.
You might find things like inappropriate
touch is not a hospitalization requiring
adverse event,
but that's an adverse event.
So just know that when you're looking
through that,
you might find there are certain things
that we could flag as an adverse event or
certain outcomes that could be flagged as
adverse and not challenging.
So that's,
but I turn that back over to the work
team need to steer me if I veer it off
course.
No, I think, I think that's it's,
it's a conversation that we need to have
a lot of.
And and I think the term integration is
something that we really need to sit with
as we walk into like how we define and
how we like structure.
The not just the research side of things.
This is more of like a global philosophy,
but if we really understand what
integration is and how that relates to
challenging experiences and where the
integration process,
that's preparation all the way through
follow up,
that is the tool that we haven't been
able to measure in standard clinical
trials.
That changes our ability to really heal
from a challenging experience.
Being faced with something that we may
not be prepared to or prepared to process
or haven't been in a place to process for
our whole lives.
And then having that brought right in
front of your eyes in a very visceral
manner and then having the support and
the time to fold those lessons back into
your life.
And that's what we need to be able to
measure to define the efficacy of our
programs.
And it's not just the medicine,
it's the process.
And I appreciate also what you all
brought together with the PATAE as a
potential partnership between Doctor
Polinski and the what we're doing here in
New Mexico.
So I feel that probably one of the next
steps we'll get into that in the next 25
minute block, but would be of course,
making a reach out and seeing if there's
some potential synergy there.
Awesome.
And we do have a committee member,
I'm not sure if they're here today,
who responded to me this morning.
And they've worked directly with Doctor
Politsky at Emory University.
They're a local New Mexican practicing
here and contributing to our community
committees.
And they are more than willing to bridge
that conversation.
I did want to address Brenda's note about
education and training.
I have a full crosswalk of committee
integrations for all of this work that we
put together and it expands beyond
adverse events all the way to every
single battery and how it's gonna affect
each individual committee's needs to
focus on like training,
clinical administration, stuff like that.
So like not not necessarily in a
directive manner,
but like more in informative as we all
figure this out sort of manner.
I'll find that link and share that in the
chat as well.
Perfect.
Thank you very much.
So we have still 2 minutes for any
questions or discussion from this
intersection group.
So I would love to,
if there's anything else, please,
like I said, leave it into the chat.
And Kate Hawk, Dr.
Jamie Beachy of Emory is here in New
Mexico, another good resource.
Fantastic.
Thank you, Kate.
I love these meetings.
Is this is how we honestly,
this is how we kind of make networking
connections.
So thank you so much for this.
This is this is wonderful to have this
working group together here.
So thanks.
So not seeing any more comments.
So I'm going to kind of like let us move
on to the next group which is from
Michelle Mirabedini and it's emergency
preparedness.
I looked through the the participant list.
I'm not seeing Michelle,
but maybe I overlooked Michelle.
Are you here?
Dan?
I am not seeing Michelle either.
Michelle,
if you might be registered under a
different name if you put it in the chat,
we can then go ahead and elevate you to a
presenter.
Yeah.
OK.
I'm not seeing Michelle or anything
that's coming up from that.
So I do want to,
I haven't heard anything because usually
I did ask if there's anything that would
come up between just let me know.
Didn't see anything.
However,
that means emergency preparedness is
still a very important part of this
committee's work.
And so I not to neglect anything that
Michelle may or may not have done,
but for anybody on this call,
I just wanted to give you a little bit of
detail, detail.
And I would love to see if there might be
somebody that could come along and assist
with this work.
Dez Bop, please raise your yes,
I didn't know if you were if somebody
might be able to unmute Dez Bop for.
Yeah, got it.
Yeah.
So just in in reference to that,
I was just wondering if there was like
you can probably put it in the chat if
there was like specific areas in which
Greg, Gregory or James might note that.
Might have a cultural considerations area
to look at just to kind of see if there
was something that from our standpoint
might, might be not a red flag,
but just something to flag for
consideration on that.
Yeah, Huge, huge recommendation.
That's a very good point.
And so Gregory and James,
I'm sure if you would be able to add and
it doesn't need to be like it's a date,
but it's between now and the May meeting
would be great.
And anything in between if because your
link is live,
then everybody would be able to see that
as well.
So that's why you might check that link a
little bit later on and see if that that
kind of section,
that idea is added there for you too.
So great recommendation.
So for emergency preparedness,
we need to kind of set like minimum
standards for facilitators and sites and
coordination with EMS and law enforcement.
We really want to make sure that the
psilocybin program is a very safe and
effective program and that clinicians
have tools and protocols in place that we
can make recommendations for.
Again,
that way that every challenging of
experience kind of I'm going to kind of
go back to let's see where it was been
kind of bringing some of these things up
and Ben's comments here is that not every
challenging experience leads immediately
to a 911 call in hospitalization.
So again,
this would be something that could
dovetail back into the challenging as
verse experiences work that James Gregory
and and and excuse me,
that Danielle that worked on.
So I just wanted to make sure that we
call that out.
So I'm spending a little time at this
point because I have a 10 minute time for
this.
So I do want to ask anybody that's on the
call now that I describe what that is and
does anybody have any like backgrounds,
information, work,
expertise in kind of this kind of idea
where it would be?
Again,
how do clinicians handle those minimum
standards for EMS and coordination and
law enforcement?
If you do have any of that,
please drop it into the chat.
Eileen just mentioned,
has anyone from LEAP participated LEAP,
anyone from LEAP here?
I would love to hear their perspective of
emergency preparedness.
Thank you.
I know fireside project is here as well,
so I don't know if there might be any
recommendations on that as well.
So,
and I'll kind of then leave it up for
James and if James might be unmuted,
then they'll be in with her with Mike.
There's a background in with my,
I have a emergency medicine background as
well.
And so we, I do a lot with the EMS crews.
I deal a lot with the docs in that type
of situation where the the first people
are going to see them and then I have
some tag them which we break resource to
expand that into some of their
educational services.
And we can work with education on that
and getting, you know,
standards out there as the team develops
them.
You know,
but those things are very challenging and
they should be handled appropriately with
the patient, you know,
at the time go away.
And so if we can get 99% of those to go
away and addressed immediately with other
things like grounding techniques,
breathing,
other type of other type of modalities
that I want to include.
Those are very important for challenging
versus adverse where you have to really
dial up and and have bigger responses.
But yeah, please include me.
Perfect.
And then we have Doctor Fatemi on and you
can be unmuted.
Sure, thank you.
And I in the comment box,
I did also see that you had said happy to
help develop our program.
Yeah, absolutely.
And you know, I agree with James.
And additionally I think if we have a
call response team where the facilitator
when they feel that they need help,
they can call and get advice on what they
need to do in this moment.
So that a challenge experience like and
also determine is this a challenging
experience or is this an adverse event.
Having that support can help that you
know, it can help the situation a lot.
Yeah, that's all I have.
Thank you.
No, thank you very much.
I appreciate that.
And just so you see in the chat box also
Gregory Evans dropped in some PATAE
covers cultural considerations.
So thank you for sharing that despot you
might mention might take a look at that
to see if it helps in,
in some of your committee work.
Shane Daniel been listening and
multitasking,
but wanted to mention I'm a PAT
integration coach.
And if the subcommittee needs perspective
from that side,
let me know when you're meeting and do I
can help.
So I would say that probably I honestly,
I'm seeing a little bit more alignment
with challenging experiences slash
adverse experiences and the emergency
preparedness side of things.
So therefore, I, I,
I'm happy if y'all wanted to kind of work
together on those kinds of things
together,
because then you're challenging
experiences as you're talking about
having these grounding techniques and
some of these other ways that your
clinicians, your therapists,
your integrations can work through that.
But then all the way into what the
adverse experiences look like.
And then how the the facilitators have
the standards and,
and protocols and such for how they then
engage with first responders and EMS and
those kind of things as as that might
progress.
So I feel that that might be something
y'all might want to look together,
maybe bring some more people on board
that are coming through here then.
Gregory Evans Additionally,
if we were tasked with customizing the
PATAE for the Mexico framework,
we get highly specific with how we frame
those needs.
Perfect.
Hana Rose agreed and Gregory Evans,
I would say that it still needs work.
Kay Hawk having the layer of call support
for emergencies and concerns would be
incredibly helpful.
Yes, that's kind of where we're going.
It's like the idea of like when does this
need to engage in the first response
slash EMS slash law enforcement need and
then Brenda Burgard having a position on
call as part of this team taking vitals
to ensure someone is not having,
for example, heart attacks or seizures.
So I'm I'm I'm going to then kind of turn
back and ask if for the team,
for Danielle and Gregory and James,
if maybe you might be able to bring a few
more people onto your your research team
to work on that to then say,
let's take it all the way from what you
have created all the way and then bring
in that emergency preparedness piece of
it.
Would that be something that I know it's
one more thing to add,
but would that dovetail well and please
push back at me if you need to because I
don't want to dump more,
but I just feel it seems to be a great
affinity to do that.
OK, thank you, Daniel.
Absolutely love to.
Can we get contacts?
Yes.
So I've again,
this is interceptional work.
There's no decisions being made at this
time.
So I feel that if there's anybody on the
call that's like 1 to work with this team
that's already started on that,
please make connections.
I think that would be fantastic to make
connections with James and Gregory and
Danielle that you wanted to work together
now to expand it into the emergency
preparedness.
So you guys rock.
I mean, this is exactly what I wanted.
This is this is how I think we're going
to have an awesome and well structured
program.
So really I cannot thank you all enough
for picking this up.
So thank you and that Will,
I'm going to kind of put an end on
emergency preparedness since we don't
have any presentation at this time.
So Eileen,
I'm going to kind of tee you up here
because I know you're on the call and
Eileen is going to be bringing in the
work that patient and community education,
core patient education for pre and intra
and post sessions.
And also one of the big things that we
need to look at is public messaging and
community harm reduction in this program
as well.
So Eileen, if you're ready,
they will go ahead and unmute you and you
can also turn your camera on.
And if you have anything to share
presentation wise,
you may do so and I'll set you up.
You stop.
I've got my little timer here,
so I'll set you up with your 10 minutes
whenever you're back.
Thanks so much.
I am trying to work out how to share my
screen.
I have, I,
I didn't really put together a
presentation, just a document,
but hopefully I can do this properly.
Perfect.
OK.
So I really looked at what other people
have been doing regarding patient
education because that was sort of what I
was tasked with and I was working alone.
So I looked at Colorado and Oregon
because obviously they are the models
that we have so far and how most people
are getting education in Colorado and
Oregon are through the websites about
their psilocybin services.
Patients are also getting education
through the provider websites as well.
So much of the initial education about
psilocybin services comes from those two
places.
Both Colorado and Oregon have like vast
resources.
There's FAQs,
there's information about who are
approved providers and there's
information like they,
they have videos and resources about what
to expect.
So that's all the the preparation before
preparation, if you will.
Obviously the preparation sessions are
going to be integral to this regulated
program that New Mexico has as far as
making sure that people are safe.
But if they're reading a little bit in
advance,
they can sort of self select as well.
In addition to that,
the Healing Advocacy Fund,
I don't know of anybody from the Healing
Advocacy Fund is all on this call today.
But like they for both states,
put together these amazing client guides
that have just tons of information about
safety, about what to expect,
all of those things.
And I have them linked here.
I'll put this in the chat afterward as
well.
So I have them linked here and I hope
that I know Healing Advocacy Fund has
been participating in this process.
So I hope that they're willing to get to
put together a client guide for New
Mexico.
Once all the rules are made and they know
what to say,
they can probably copy paste a lot of the
things that they've already done.
Colorado's also done a public education
campaign on social media.
They have some in person and some online
listening sessions as well.
I couldn't really find anything like in
Oregon about that,
but I imagine that Oregon did a lot of
that kind of stuff prior to measure one O
9 passing and measure 110 as well.
But as we know from looking at what
happened with Oregon and measure 110 is
that it was ultimately repealed because
there wasn't enough public education.
There weren't enough public resources for
what was happening outside of the
psilocybin space.
So it's important for us to consider what
who is going to be using psilocybin in
New Mexico that's outside of this
regulated program as well.
Because as Rand has reported, you know,
8 million people used psilocybin in 2023
and 11 million people use psilocybin in
2025.
And in 2023, about 10,
000 of those people had done it in a
regulated situation and everybody else
had done it outside of the regulated
situation.
And we can expect that I,
I don't have the numbers for Colorado.
I couldn't find them.
I'm sure they're out there.
I just couldn't take them up.
But we can expect that most of the people
in New Mexico who use psilocybin,
as they see more publicity about
psilocybin,
as they see this regulated process come
through,
they're not going to use them in this
useless assignment in the regulated
setting.
So there's kind of this additional
responsibility to do this bigger,
larger public education campaign.
The approaches in Oregon and Colorado are
both excellent.
They've done a lot of really great work.
But I think that New Mexico can expand on
that.
I think that New Mexico can obviously use
the New Mexico Health Department that
already has harm reduction services
readily available,
but many people are going to be hesitant
to access that.
We have underserved,
marginalized and historically oppressed
populations that are not going to be
interested in getting their information
from the government because the
government has been the ones to oppress
them.
So there's a fair amount of of other
resources we can have,
but there's also a fair amount of
misinformation out there.
So I think that New Mexico is going to
need to evaluate the resources that are
out there and choose which ones will be
part of a public education campaign,
APSA or whatever.
I've listed here some of the national
organizations that do this kind of
education.
Also on the Colorado website,
they list things like the Fireside
Project, like Zendo,
like all of those things that you
definitely want to make sure are part of
this process.
I love that there's somebody from
Fireside on this call today.
So we want to make sure that that all of
these resources are available,
but also people have like the knowledge
of like set and setting all of those
things.
And you can do that through these public
education things that lots of national
organizations have done.
However,
if we really want to meet those
marginalized populations,
we're definitely going to want to make
sure that we have local resources
available to people who already know how
to get into and connect with the
communities or are already part of the
community, the communities.
So like the New Mexico Harm Reduction
Collaborative really focuses right now on
high risk substances,
but they have a lot of knowledge that we
could use to access the communities that
are going to need this education.
And maybe you already do need this
education and don't have it.
There's also the community Opioid
Response Education program that is is
great as far as opioid response,
but they're going to maybe have some
suggestions for for this program as far
as how they developed a virtual program
to teach people about harm reduction in
that space.
Other considerations is consider how
public education can focus on encouraging
participation in data collection.
There's a lot of hesitants around sharing
data.
And I know that other that another
committee is working on that as well as
like we talked about data collection here.
But I think that we can,
New Mexico has a unique opportunity to
maybe incorporate that into public
education, Say why it's important,
say how you won't be identified or
targeted if you share your information
and say how that could help so many other
people if people are sharing their their
information.
And then last,
I just want to say with evaluation of
outside programs,
it might be important to consider if they
have good research to back up their
program concepts.
If they're using fear tactics to say,
you know,
you're going to think you're a glass of
orange juice for the rest of your life.
If you take psilocybin once and consider
positive language rather than language
that furthers myths,
make sure that they they have that
research to back it up.
So that's what I've put together so far
and I'd love to hear some comments.
Thank you.
Well, I have to say Eileen,
if you weren't noticed saying that as you
were speaking,
you had lots of hearts and lots of claps.
So it was fantastic work that you have
put together on it.
And I think you hit the heart of exactly
what we need or tasked with in this
committee.
It is also all of the harm reduction
outside of this.
So you've,
you've already got a great start.
I would really love because again,
as you called out,
Caroline is here with Fireside Project
and of course there are plenty of other
people on this call that probably have a
a lot of affinity in this space too.
Eileen needs you.
Eileen needs your help.
So I want to use this next 10 minutes of
comments to kind of have y'all kind of
talk in your chat box,
like share so that Eileen can bring you
into this work because in the next 25
minutes we're going to talk about next
steps and such.
So Kate Eileen dropped and so I missed
Doctor Fathimi thank you for missing
amazing meeting to teach integration to
our Academy students.
Go for it.
Thank you Eileen dropped the chat in the
chat box the link to this doc so you can
see this offline.
Kate Hawk happy to see the realistic
comprehensive approach to education
wondering about supporting quality drug
education in schools.
I run substance abuse prevention programs
for students.
I think that this is going to be as
exactly what Eileen had called out.
It's like when we're talking about public
education campaigns,
are they based upon reality or are they
based upon negative language and fear?
Our job is to ensure that if there are
community education and school education
programs that it is grounded in reality
and not in those things we just mentioned.
So please, I would love for people to.
And we've got 10 minutes.
So if you do feel like I don't want to
type it all, I want to raise my hand.
Go ahead.
We've got some time.
We we kind of accelerated the time.
So anybody care to kind of share anything
that Eileen has brought to the table here?
And especially who wants to team up with
Eileen on this because there's a lot of
kind of next steps that she's outlined.
I keep monitoring.
Oh, there we go.
Thank you, James, please.
I think that you'll be unmuted and can
share highly an amazing work.
Thank you so much.
Question for you on this,
What do you think are best social media?
There's so much stuff about social media
platforms.
What's our biggest push here?
What do you think out there right now?
You know, kids use one thing,
adults or people are already going to be
using another thing.
So where do you think the the DoH or
everybody should kind of your thoughts on
what's our biggest opportunity or focus
point that we could go after with that?
What's, what's your thought?
Are you asking about like what platforms
we should focus on or are you asking
about like what strategies we should
focus on?
And yes, Caroline,
I see your comment and the chat.
I would love to connect with you as well.
A little bit of both.
There's, you know,
there's everything out there right now,
from Facebook to Instagram to lawsuits to
non to, you know,
so many different opportunities here that
money, time and spent is going to matter.
You know, like you were saying,
so kind of a little bit of both.
So that's kind of a long answer,
but I'll try.
OK, it I,
I just got a master's degree in
communications of excited.
I get to use a little of of of my my
knowledge.
Really picking a a social media platform
depends on who it is that you are trying
to attract.
If you want to attract 40 year old men,
you want to use YouTube.
If you want to attract 14 year old girls,
you want to use TikTok.
So we want to attract.
If you want to attract people who are me,
you want to use Facebook,
We want we want to hit on everybody.
And there are there are rograms that you
can use to cross OST messages on multiple
platforms.
However,
it's a little more complicated than that
because what is going to make me read is
not what's going to make my 14 year old
daughter read.
She does not care about the language that
I would use to talk about things.
So it's it is going to be a little of
trying to create resources that the
demographic is going to connect with.
And what I connect with is not what a
person of color is necessarily going to
connect with.
And when in New Mexico,
there's a large Native American
population and they may have more
education on these topics than than we do,
but how we connect with them is going to
be very different as well.
So unfortunately, yes,
time and resources and money is all a
factor.
But unfortunately,
if you want to reach all of these
different groups,
it is going to have to be a multimodal
approach to reaching it.
And then what you say is also so going to
have to,
to change based on who you're reaching.
There can be some basics though, like,
you know, just 10 points,
like set and setting, like, you know,
considering your other substances that
you're using at the time, like having a,
a, a trusted care partner who is sober,
having a sober sitter, you know,
there are like bullet points that you can
hit and then just how you say it to the
different audiences changes a little bit.
I hope that answers you.
That was fantastic.
I appreciate it.
And I'm glad that you called out some of
the equity work.
You know,
that Desba can definitely kind of like
dovetail in some of this stuff with as
well.
And also during your presentation,
you're calling out the fact that some of
the trusted messengers in this, of course,
Department of Health would be a trusted
messenger, but again,
would it land for every kind of message
and it may not.
So therefore,
having other trusted messengers and this
system is very critical as well.
And you've outlined several that are out
there.
So fantastic work.
Next one that was up is Hannah Rose.
Hi there.
Yeah, Thank you so much, Eileen.
Really nice to hear your perspectives
about education and what came to mind
while listening to you and listening to
this last dialogue is asking ourselves,
how do us asking ourselves individually,
how do we want to show up?
You know,
are we more inspired to connect on a
local level and make an impact locally or
on a larger scale?
And so my curiosities are around having
an education aspect of the medical
psilocybin program and what would that
look like also around partnering,
you mentioned some organizations,
Eileen partnering with with these
organizations.
So if we had a really organized resource
based resource document that even broke
it down,
like how do we want to make an impact
local and then it was organized on a
local level bigger scale, you know,
then we as participate participants in
this program, however we're participating,
we can know how to take action and make
an impact.
Thank you.
I think those are such excellent points.
And the good news is,
is that some of that work has already
been done.
Students for Sensible Drug Policy has
like this master list of resources that
is so comprehensive.
The only thing that I think that we would
have to add to it is the the state and
local resources that might be be unique.
I just think it's such a good point,
Eileen.
I think that that would be great.
If if you do want to move down that
pathway,
then that's one of the asks that you can
make of the committee is to say like, OK,
this is a gap that we have.
Doesn't have to be all on you.
It could be like,
you can like outline it and then just say
here's the gap.
That's part of the next step.
So yeah, you're not on your own on that.
So.
And then Hana, back to Hana on this one.
Yeah.
One more.
Thank you.
One more quick thing.
I,
as somebody that has extensive training
in nonviolent communication and authentic
mindful communication,
I liked that you pointed out
deconstructing and using mindful
communication around this.
And that doesn't mean that just because
we're here on this call and then this
meeting that we know do that a lot of our
communication patterns are really
embedded in US.
And so I also like the idea of having a
training program within the medical
psilocybin program on how to deconstruct
these limiting belief language and
thought patterns and self reflect So we
know, oh gosh,
where am I holding these assumptions and
biases and limiting beliefs as well.
So again, thank you,
Eileen for speaking to that.
Appreciate that.
So much more eloquent than how I said it.
Beautiful.
Hello, Gregory Evans.
I'll let you come up next and then we'll
go to Dasbot.
Thank you and very glad to see the work
that you put together.
I mean,
my contact is on some of the stuff from
earlier,
so feel free to reach out to me if you
want assistance organizing and
disseminate,
like preparing things for dissemination.
That's just an open door that can be for
universal for everyone.
What I was really curious about is do we
have anyone from the department's
training in it,
like the education team associated with
this program?
Do we have anyone in there that can like
be partnership level, not waiting,
not like kind of interstitial work with
those teams that are in place and should
be actively working on this to
collaborate it?
Like do we have those relationships
mapped out?
That's a good point.
I think that nominee,
you mentioned that there were educators
from the department here too.
Yes.
So a couple of items on that is we
actually have four health educators and a
program manager within our center and
they are working on educational material.
It was really great to see all of this
information from you, Eileen.
For those who are here who have known me
for many years,
and there's quite a few here,
one of the things that we look at is to
ensure that we have harm reduction
practices throughout.
And part of the reason why I can help and
guarantee that those sort of things will
happen is because if anybody here has
actually gone through the New Mexico
Department of Health harm reduction
training at any point,
and I just kind of like to see real Quick
dead by.
I know you've got your hand up to make a
point, so we'll keep that in mind.
But if you can raise your hand real quick,
who's gone through that training here?
OK.
Some of our staff, but nobody else,
that's actually a training that is
offered throughout the state.
And part of the reason why we have some
of our staff who has gone have gone
through it is that training was actually
initiated over 15 years ago and I created
that curriculum and continue to help with
them.
I used to manage that program.
And so for those who are not familiar,
it used to be the medical cannabis and
harm reduction program.
And so we ensure that those sort of
aspects are included within it and we'll
continue to do so.
So yes,
we do have the expertise already within
the center.
We work with the harm reduction program
on a regular basis,
talk with them about different trainings,
educations and to be able to do this.
And so yes,
we are here and it is a part of what
we're here to help with.
But remember right now part of these
committee meetings are actually to hear
from the communities and we don't want to
over shadow that.
And so that's just one thing to remember
is we're here to help and we will help.
And that's there's no question on that
side.
But we also want to ensure that we don't
inhibit what the communities and
different people want to bring in and
ensure that they're bringing it in
without us simply turning around and
saying, oh, we're going to do it this way.
And I hope that helps with regard to that.
Thank you very much and Don appreciate
that.
And it's good to know that we've got a
team that's behind us on that.
So Eileen,
as as you and your group kind of come to
this, then I guess that you're not alone.
We're in the Burgard says possibly need
to have social media specialist.
And Eileen,
I haven't been I haven't been in New
Mexico,
but I've gone through the training Des.
But I know you're had your hand up and
we've got and then I saw Dexter raise his
hand.
But or Dexter.
So you raised your hand.
I want to make sure that but did you did
you have comment please unmute if you can
and need to.
Yes, I yeah, thank you.
Thank you, Dan.
Yeah.
So just a couple of notes.
This is also to the to the general public
in the meeting and then also speaking to
the choir with the DoH type of deal.
In my understanding, you know,
government work is very limited and based
on budgets and what they have the
capability of in in place.
But then also with the recommendations
that we're going to be providing to them
on the specificity of how in particular
psilocybin education.
And thank you, Eileen,
for the note on the Native American
communities.
And then also Dominic,
Dominic pointed a little bit to this just
a second ago about, you know,
whether or not how,
how we're going to go into these
communities and how we speak to them and
how we are able to,
to address their issues.
One thing I just kind of wanted to point
out and keep in mind, again,
this is just for the general public is,
you know,
we have a lot of this way of speaking,
especially in the psilocybin communities
about our mindfulness,
about our practices and about alignments
and about, you know, we,
we have like we're,
we kind of sort of created this other
type of, of way of communicating.
And sometimes when it comes to
communicating with the masses is to keep
it simple.
What are the most common ways in which we
can bridge understanding that is not
harmful, that is more in alignment,
that is in ways that specific communities
might be able to understand.
And some of these communities that we are
going to be educating in addition to
might be more on the religious side,
might be more on, you know, I would,
I would want to say opposite,
But we not always the case of, of,
of our own way of looking at the world.
And we have to be mindful of how we're
coming off of being overly righteous or
overly knowledgeable about this,
what what we're doing and how we're doing
it.
But really to be in a place of listening,
as Dominic was saying, like,
what do the community need?
And especially as Eileen pointed out,
you know, this government,
essentially how are we looking at it when
it comes to marginalized groups have been
oppressed by the government and also by
colonization over hundreds of years.
What does that look like when we're
trying to say,
here's the pathway to freedom?
Great, wonderful.
But you know,
it's just like here we are prosecuting
and, and, and completely, you know,
running over these types of communities.
And now we're saying here,
let's show you a pathway forward in this
particular Safeway.
But yes,
I really appreciate Eileen's pointing
that out.
And it also,
I feel like the recommendation
specifically might be to have someone
that might be more on the,
what does that look like on the other
side of things?
And not saying that the Department of
Health doesn't already do this with their
website.
So I'm mostly on Facebook.
So that's what I see is, you know,
that outreach,
but what I'm hearing from Eileen is,
you know,
this really has to be targeted if we're
going to be able to provide it for,
you know,
these multiple social media levels and
also multi generational, but also just,
you know,
cross understanding between different
varying levels of education, spirituality,
everything, you know, and,
and every single spectrum.
And what does that look like, Dez?
But thank you very much for that because
that's,
it is so important to bring this work
into that.
So love, love that you call that out.
And I think that that's one of our key
critical points is to work very closely
together, as you said before,
to make sure those messages reach well,
got about two minutes.
I do want to make sure Dexter gets in
before we go to our next point,
which is convergence and next steps.
And then so Dexter,
if you would unmute and kind of share
your comment the next two minutes, am I,
I think I'm unmuted.
Yeah,
I'm a veteran and I think the veteran
community is a unique group.
And therefore I would would love to have
training or collaboration with any
educational group.
And I'd like to know where to start.
Who, who would I reach out to?
Are you talking about general education
or are you talking for facilitator
education for specifically for the
psilocybin program?
I know, I know.
I would love to get an early start in
helping veterans understand what to
expect when this is when this is finally
rolled out.
I see.
Perfect.
I'm going to yes.
Thank you, Donna,
I was going to say please.
I think you don't.
Yeah.
Thank you, Dan, and thank you, Dexter.
One of the things that will be happening
as the program gets established,
as the rules and regulations are are put
out there,
then we'll be conducting various
outreaches and various educational
sessions for different groups and
individuals.
And veterans are, of course,
one of the primary groups that we'll be
reaching out to,
as well as Native American and other
marginalized communities because we do
know that there's a definite need,
need in those areas.
So we'll be doing that.
What I would say the best thing right now,
because those plans are not in place yet,
because we can't really start talking
about it until we have, you know,
the rest of it as far as where are people
going to be able to get services,
you know, more information on it.
And so for right now,
the best thing I would say is keep
watching on our website,
attend some of these meetings because as
that information is available,
we'll be putting it out there.
And definitely there will also be
trainings for people in the public on how
they can help with outreach as well.
So I hope that helps with regard to that.
Thank you.
That's perfect.
Thank you.
And Dexter,
just to say this also because Eileen is
working on patients and community
education, be very close.
And maybe if there are certain aspects
that you can share and bring into this as
well,
just as Desmond mentioned that there are
different audiences,
we need to be mindful of, please,
you know, bring,
bring your expertise to this as well.
We're moving in and I apologize, James,
I'm going to get your comment that you
read and then probably catch you back up
again.
We're moving into our last kind of a
little bit here.
We do have Hanna that's by yes,
cultural sensitivity is essential and
this requires education on our part about
what this means,
how to serve with cultural and sensitive
embodiment.
James said we need to have a pairing of
integration focus with education of the
public and Hanna back again.
This is a pinnacle of social work
practice and maybe there is an
opportunity for partnership and education
with the social work profession,
the medical suicide program.
Fantastic comments everybody.
And we're moving into now our convergence
and next steps.
So there's a couple of things I wanted to
hit in this one just so we can wrap this
meeting up and say we've got some action
that we've we're working forward to and
what our next steps are.
So we do want to talk about for each
topic,
what are one to three and probably 1 is
great recommendations for each topic,
meaning the challenging adverse
experiences,
what's one of the most important things
we need to do next for emergency
preparedness?
What is one of the next thing that we
need for that?
And then for the patient and community
education,
what's one thing we need for that?
So for each of the committee,
the subcommittee groups that have
ownership of this,
I would love for you to kind of just say
like, but this is what I need.
Meaning it's like this is what we're
going to do or what I need from the
community at large here.
And let's see if we can get some help
from the rest of this group here.
Also in this time,
I do want to talk about any parking lot
items or blind spots,
things that we're missing.
But essentially what this 25 minute.
Will be is what are the interstitial
groups next steps and what can we come
back in May with to especially?
I want y'all to be able to kind of come
to some consensus on some of their work
so that we can move forward on that to
say, Yep, this is perfect,
Let's move on this and let's continue on
this.
So this is for each one of y'all that had
work in the group.
So of course,
James and and Gregory and and Danielle,
I want to make sure.
And Eileen,
please kind of share on that one or two,
three kind of topics that you need help
with or you're moving forward on between
now and May 8.
And this is this is an allscape.
So any of y'all there you go.
James Golford.
Hey Dan for our group and I won't talk to
everybody.
And again, you know,
Greg Gregory chirp in here.
Definitely that cultural sensitivity and
access type of thing that was brought up.
I think that will be a focus of ours is
encompassing that ideas like that group.
What else can were we missing and our
great ideas like that?
Cultural sensitivity and other things?
And Gregory,
I think that for your group also,
you had mentioned that maybe reaching out
to Emory and I believe I saw some kind of
work on that too.
Is that one of the next steps you all
have as well?
Well, I think you know what,
I have a whole document on that pathway
for connecting,
but I think what we specifically need is
to program approval essentially.
Like does the program want to explore
this conversation and do we want to
approach it as a partnership or do we
want to take the domain and own it
separate from the Politsky publication?
And then, yeah.
And then after that we reach out through
official like we can have soft
conversations,
but there needs to be decision of who in
the department or in the board does the
official ask and starts that conversation.
I'm going to make a recommendation again,
I'll my recommendation for just that.
So I need, you know,
as anybody's push back on that.
I think that personally like a soft
contact would be great to see if there is
some kind of like this could work.
We won't know exactly what that looks
like.
And I feel that maybe for our May 8th
meeting is that you can present kind of a
proposal of what that would look like,
whatever and it might be.
Here's two different paths or three
different paths of what that might look
like.
And then that way we as a committee could
then make that vote and say this is the
one to kind of go down,
especially with the advice coming back
from, you know,
Dominic on this and the rest of the DoH
team.
But I think that that would be a, a great,
I think that would be a solid next step
if y'all could make that soft contact.
What do you feel?
That's just recommendation definitely.
And we'll like that that'll happen
shortly.
And I think just including all of the
people that are in the conversation in
that.
But under like,
I think we need to understand that the
ideas that we are creating an instrument
that does not exist and that means
something on a mag like that is a massive
thing.
Like we're still using instruments
designed in 1916,
over a century later in this work,
we're still informed by those instruments.
So by doing this, it's massive.
But outside of that,
I'm still kind of collecting my thoughts
about what we need contributions wise for
interstitial work.
But OK, there's a lot.
Yeah.
And I think because again,
it's just like one,
we're we're taking this elephant one bite
at a time.
So this is their, you know,
just you've kind of got a great outline
for everything.
And that way you can say that this is
kind of the next Sprint that we have for
this.
So from from that aspect,
I'm glad everybody's kind of sharing con
contact information to do this work
offline and to support and help in this
because it's kind of this is a lot of
work.
You're exactly right.
We can't get it done in the one hour,
2 hours we have these meetings.
So and you can't do it by yourself.
So James,
thanks for bringing up if you do need to
work with Desva on anything on the
cultural side,
please definitely make that contact as
well.
I think it's huge and I think that makes
a big thing.
And then for Gregory with the contact
with on the Polisky side and then coming
back,
but like here's the pathways that we can
go down with that.
Eileen for your and of course,
I'm sorry because emergency preparedness.
I know that that was one of the things
for that I've asked y'all to take on
since it dovetails well.
So anything on standards for facilitation
and states for working with the protocols,
EMS and law enforcement,
especially on the adverse experience side
and such and where we could go in that
direction.
And then Eileen, how about you?
What,
what kind of next step do you see between
now and may to, to work together and what,
what help and what support do you need
that maybe this community can help with?
And I need people to say like, yes,
I can help Eileen with that too.
So, yeah, so got so much great feedback.
So I took notes in the document that I
prepared.
So I want to start to build out some of
these other suggestions that people have,
like drug education in schools.
I want to start to look at like what's
being done and, and what could be done.
But one thing that I really want to say
that I need a lot of help with because I
work primarily in the pain space where
the preparation,
administration and integration sessions
aren't really as much of a thing.
I don't know a ton of real information
about integration.
Like I know what my practices are,
but that's A and A1.
If anybody could could join and help with
the recommendations for the public
education about integration,
that would be like massively appreciated.
Thank you.
And I'm,
I'm going to throw out a name just
because I I've known Katherine Warnock,
but that's somebody that I feel.
And if anybody is out here on the call
that has contact with her,
maybe that might be somebody to connect
Eileen up with.
That's a recommendation.
Doesn't mean anything else besides that.
So,
but anybody want to kind of share if I'm
on the right track or if you've got
another recommendation to connect with
Eileen?
I I think that would be a good one.
I can probably do the connection if
there's no one else that's there.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And say Brenda and Hora.
Hora got the C2.
Oh, oh, yeah.
Brenda's here,
so maybe she can refer to that.
I'll, I'll go ahead, Brenda,
thank you very much.
So yes,
I can definitely connect you Eileen to
Catherine.
We,
we do converse a lot about what education
looks like along with other,
other people out there in the community
and other teachers that have been out
there.
So yes, definitely I can,
I got your e-mail address,
Eileen and I can go ahead and e-mail you
Catherine's information.
And actually,
she's going to be the speaker today from
1:00 to 3:00 today in my training and
education.
So yes, I,
I really would love to see more and more
people get together about forming the
curriculum,
what that's going to look like.
Like Dan,
you're doing such a wonderful job with
moving everybody together.
I,
I'm not going to do any heavy lifting
here.
This is just phenomenal.
So agreed, the, the experts are out.
Y'all know that that's all I could do is
I think about as like when you're in a
Symphony, the conductor's just doing this.
Everybody's actually making the music.
So that's what y'all do.
The the The thing is,
is that clinicians really who have
already have certification and training
are chomping at the bit to start to
practice.
And even though that a lot of us who have
been practicing, who've been teaching,
we are used to the protocols, you know,
the the history of New Mexico,
integrating that what that's going to
look like for a culturally speaking.
You know,
I think one of the main things here is
that this is really great because we're
really getting into the details here in
your meeting about what this is all going
to look like.
But everybody's just, you know,
getting ready to, to to to make this leap.
So thank you very much.
And yes, again, Eileen,
I will connect to you with Catherine.
Thank you.
And I'll be at the session later today
because I really want to hear.
So I'll be there.
Thank you.
Awesome.
And Doctor Trucker,
I see that you had unmuted your
microphone and went back on mute.
I wanted to call out if you did need to
say anything.
And I've been talking over you.
No, I am fine.
Thank you very much.
OK.
No,
I just so I come off you and I just
didn't want to like ignore that.
OK, Thank you very much for that.
One of the other things that I've run
into.
So I,
I think that all the groups kind of have
at least you make connections,
which is fantastic.
You've got people that can help you with
your next steps.
Absolutely love that.
And I'm going to hit a couple of comments
in here that I, I mentioned missed here.
So Eileen,
to put in contact information and please
feel free to reach out if you need help
and recommendations and feel free to
comments right in that document shared,
James shared his contact information.
Hana Rose integration is a vital part of
effective psilocybin healing.
This is an area I know well and would
love to share with you, Eileen.
So I'm glad you all are kind of sharing
the contact information there as well.
And that's now been placed in there.
So awesome.
The other I I love it.
I love, like I said,
y'all are the ones making wonderful music
for New Mexico.
And kind of go back to Eileen's point
about there's some wonderful work in like
the Zendo project Fireside and such
that's out there,
but we need to make a very specific to
New Mexico.
Gregory call that out as well.
The idea with utilizing some of these
techniques that's going to grow a
wonderful New Mexico program and kind of
just I just got to share.
It was like,
I really want this to be like,
I want people to go, man.
New Mexico knew exactly what they were
doing.
They they built a program that is not
just we've got psilocybin out here,
but it's like we've got a safe,
we've got a, a, a home grown program,
something that the rest of the country is
really going to look at.
So I'm so excited about the work that
this group has been doing and sharing and
the expertise that y'all bring to that.
Carolyn Krolan I'd like to note the
executive director on the fireside
project will be joining the next meeting
to discuss our organization's work in the
space.
I love it.
So that would be fantastic.
I would love as y'all are working on that
because again,
this would be a great when we do this
intersectional breakout again that that
would be a time for the the executive
director to kind of share along with
Eileen at that time.
So y'all kind of coordinate that as part
of the presentation.
I would love that.
The other thing that I do know is that
like I said,
what what both Eileen has shared,
what Gregory has shared with James and
Danielle, those documents, please, please,
please review them between now and May
8th and come to the May 8th meeting.
Because we'll spend some time at the
beginning of that meeting talking about
that work and any kind of issues that
anybody might have, questions,
comments that everybody might have.
Because what I would like to do is to
again,
revisit some of the the protocols that we
had agreed on before and make those
changes that both that the team has kind
of shared.
Eileen shared a lot of great resources
and of course, the James,
Danielle and Gregory team shared a lot of
resources.
I want to make sure we can update that as
well.
So we'll be able to converge that too.
And then with some of the time that we
have left in this beep and we've got
about 10 minutes parking lot and blind
spot ideas.
So again, this is a time,
this is this is research and continuous
improvement.
So I need everybody that's on the call to
kind of share anything that is outside of
the topics that we talked about today or
like I said,
blind spots that we really need to work
on in this group because.
And if you do share something,
I hate to tell you this,
but because again, I was a teacher,
usually when somebody asks me a question,
I said, great,
you're the one that's going to research
that.
So I'm just calling that out.
Probably nobody's going to say anything
now.
And I don't want to,
I don't want to do that to you.
Don't threaten me, Dan.
I like,
I know somebody's going to be on the call
going, Oh, I'm ready, I'm ready.
I got so but for this group and again,
focus on what we can do what what this
group can do because there's other
committees that are doing other work.
But if that is something that is cross
pollination, but I can, you know,
we can definitely make sure the other
groups are there to hear what you might
say.
That's kind of what the parking lot idea
is for.
So yeah,
start raising your hands and let's put
some stuff in the chat.
And so Desvar, you're the first one up.
Hi.
Hi, Dan.
So yeah, I,
I kind of will make good on your
suggestion there.
Just a quick note.
I think that for the sake of kind of not
overdoing everything,
I did take a quick Lance.
I'm on my phone too, by the way.
So this is a very quick glance at the
flagging area where Greg and James's
presentation was for the socio cultural
issues that might result of that.
I think that for the sake again of kind
of and and this is for everybody else too
who there's anything in particular that
might be on the cultural considerations,
access, etcetera.
Kind of maybe flagging that in a copy
paste way where that one can also be in
its own sort of parking lot for the
cultural considerations aspect of it.
And then I wanted to say maybe
specifically, you know,
parentheses Native American.
And the reason why I'm saying parentheses
Native American because we do have other
considerations that are cultural here in
specifically New Mexico.
It's a very, very diverse.
But since we do have a large population
of Native Americans and I do have people
who are asking specifically for what that
looks like for Native Americans and
specifically,
specifically for federal tribes and their
sovereignty.
And the reason why saying copy paste and
put off to the side as like kind of
almost a separate document with these
social cultural considerations is that
way if there is a website,
which will be my recommendation perhaps
to the department,
if there isn't 1 already that I am aware
of, that tribes can go to,
that these nations can be able to just,
you know, quick tab,
look at what these things might be.
Because sometimes it is just a matter of
I do,
I do look for those kind of quick tabs.
I do look for the information that might
be specifically targeted to a specific
group such as myself.
And so I think that it might be helpful
for the other committees and anyone else
looking at that to just maybe have it set
aside that these are the ones that we
feel might be flags for cultural
considerations,
maybe specifically Native American tabs
for whatever they're looking at.
And I'm going to keep in mind for May 8th
because my committee is on the 28th.
Perfect.
Thank you very much for sharing.
I'm glad that you got that out to
everything because that's a perfect one
spot that we've got to kind of hit
Gregory next and then over to James.
I think to what Desba was saying.
If we because I don't want to spend any
more time talking about the Polzki thing.
But if if there is a team,
I think having a represent representation
from the committee,
probably having Desba involved in that
conversation is a great way to approach
those modifications.
But OK, number one,
I've said it before and I'll say it again.
We need to include chemical
fingerprinting research like our this
work group has primarily been focused on
getting instruments and measurements on
the therapy and the the the program kind
of outputs.
But what we're not looking at and what I
would like to at some point when it's
appropriate start to look at what the
chemical analysis of the medicine is and
how those unique fingerprints can layer
into specific types of therapy.
We have like our four main channels and
let's figure out if there is nuance that
we can do to amplify and specify types of
medicine.
That's one.
I also think that we can parking lot and
probably bring it in sooner than later
the integration of the end,
end of life research because I think
that's kind of a gap that we're missing
in the data that we're collecting.
So I want to kind of mark that I want to
make sure that we start to track or we
build in the infrastructure to track
participant dropouts where people drop
out of the program and why and if there's
not a reason or whatever.
And then that brings me to like the other
conversation around the infrastructure
and the tools that we're going to be
using to collect and disseminate this
information.
Thank you very much.
I put all those down on the parking lot
idea because those are great,
like next actions that we can look at for
our next meeting too.
So fantastic.
And then James.
Hey, Dan,
one idea that I had just one thought here
because I haven't heard it yet.
You know,
it kind of goes back to the education
side is really the difference between a
medical model and a recreational what
language.
We need to be very careful.
My experience again,
is that once we announce this,
it doesn't matter what language we use
out there,
people are going to even be more curious
and be more willing to try this
themselves.
And without really saying you only can do
the medical way, you know, how,
how are we going to do that?
I don't know.
It's a bigger question for the DoH.
But that's a big thing, you know,
is we don't want to channel these people
to the recreational side.
We want to channel them to the medical
side and,
and that's going to be a big challenge
and a big step up.
And,
and the way we word that in education and
just follow through.
I don't know.
It's going to be something I didn't know
if there was thoughts or ideas because I
just thought that was something we hadn't
discussed yet.
Thank you.
Personally, I love that.
And,
and the nice thing about this is we've
got a couple of minutes left on it.
So I get to have a few comments here,
but that's great work on Eileen's,
you know, working group as well.
And now I'm going to throw it over to
Brenda.
Well, thank you, James, for that.
Yeah.
So, you know,
what would recreational look like?
You know, with the medical model,
I think safety is always the best way to
go.
I mean, once you put the safety at,
it's really up to the individual who is
going to do that on their own.
Education and safety is, is, is paramount.
Doesn't matter if it's medical or
recreational, safety is always paramount.
And that's where fireside comes in.
You know,
there's the number to call if people are
running into trouble because as human
beings,
we like to experiment and we like to DYIA
lot of things.
And we don't know exactly how much
trouble we could get ourselves into
because, you know,
a large part of us are risk takers.
And for example,
I was talking to a nurse the other day
and she she does do things recreationally.
I'm not going to mention what she does,
but The thing is,
is that everyone is doesn't really know
about this program.
And when I was talking about it, oh,
there's a program for this, it's like,
yes, there is.
And I have to remind myself lots of times,
James,
that a lot of people don't know what
we're doing here,
even in our own backyard.
So it's,
it's very interesting to see how we're
going to disseminate this information and
get it out there to the public.
As you know, you know,
the president of Decrim for psychedelics
work here in New Mexico.
It's just basically just like kind of
just a holding spot right there for
people to start to know that there's,
there's, there is something out there.
However,
I think people are just laser focused on
on social media and not and,
and just taking bit bits and pieces and
cherry picking here to see what's going
to happen.
So yeah, back to my main point,
safety is always the best way to go.
And you know,
we don't want to push one way or the
other,
but we want to make sure that people are
knowledgeable on whatever route they're
going to take.
Hey, be safe out there.
Perfect.
Thank you, Brent.
You're exactly right.
And like I said,
that's the the the work that Eileen and
the rest of the people that are helping
with Eileen's going to be really focusing
on those kind of messages.
I'm going to since we're at the last 15
minutes,
which is now the public comment and close
out everybody keep your hands up that
we're already had your hands up because
this is now moving into your time where I
really shut that up and I'm not going to
talk.
But Shane McConnell McDaniel said,
if you want a good contact for integrated
coaching coaching,
I recommend reaching out to being true to
you transformation coaching and training.
And the link is there.
So true, James,
thank you very much up there.
And so now we move into public comments
close out.
We're going to reconvene this group May
8th at 9:00 to 11:00.
So make sure you mark on your calendar.
I really appreciate this group and the
same consistency that y'all have been
showing coming to this and that'll be of
course,
the interstitial work will come over to
this.
If anybody has Michelle Amir of Bodini's
e-mail or contact information,
because they might want to get in contact
with Gregory, James, and Danielle,
drop it into the chat or anybody that can
get them in connection would be great.
And so I'd love to see you all back at
that May 8th meeting.
And if you have to drop off completely
understand.
But this is now your time.
This is public comment.
So make sure that if you would like to
make a public comment,
keep your hands up and then we'll open
your mic for you for the last 13 minutes.
So Debra, you're up first.
Hi, thank you, Dan, to James's comment.
I just wanted to point out too, yeah,
we definitely the the specific the
specific concern that we have for this
particular program is the medical.
And I think that, you know, the DoH will,
you know, figure out what language it's,
it's kind of almost like a branding.
You know,
we have DoH has to be on brand for what
their how they're doing it and how
they're conducting because it's
restricted by the program that that is
being rolled out.
So when it comes to, you know,
whether or not people are of their own
volition reaching out and doing the
recreational, yes, to Brenda's point,
to Brenda's point, it does, you know,
the websites could definitely be more
broad and it's, you know,
these are the the recommendations we have
is that it maybe it's more more broad and
to just not forget that that the DOA
should not forget that it might be more
broad in what possible connections that
might be might be made.
I don't know if they can do connections
to fireside.
I don't know if they can do connections
or these are the hotlines that you can
talk to in that way,
But maybe that might be a recommendations
or here are some other avenues if you
feel like you are crisis hotlines.
These are types of the things that people
can and that these are also not.
These are private, private,
private organizations that are doing
their own things that are not associated
with the duh because those are things
that are definitely going to be into
consideration.
And I'm only saying that for for the sake
of the public that there it's almost like
there's two different things.
There's the branding and and I mean,
that's very loosely.
I'm not saying that that is what the duh
is saying,
but the duh has a very specific concern
for medical psilocybin for where we're at.
But I think it's a good point that for
the instance of education,
what does that look like?
Because people are going to ask what's
the difference between medical psilocybin,
What's the difference between psilocybin
and in general,
and what's the difference between magic
mushrooms?
In essence,
it's basically where it's coming from I
think is kind of what, you know,
maybe the education part needs to come.
The medical psilocybin is coming from
these specified growers and cultivators,
etcetera.
That is being facilitated through these
particular specialists and that's all.
And then, you know,
that might be leaving that gap where say
the Organization for Decriminalized
Psychedelics,
New Mexico might then fill that gap.
Then there's all this other stuff,
then there's all these other things.
If you need more information,
these are the places that you can go to.
But I think that for the sake of
understanding, for the general public,
for ourselves,
we just kind of keep those things in mind
that there is the government side,
medical psilocybin through the
facilitators,
through these networks and these channels.
And then there's everything else.
And we kind of,
sort of don't talk about everything else,
but we also do provide safety in that
sense.
Appreciate that.
And Gregory, you got 3 minutes.
I just wanted to like walk through some
language that I heard there and like
focus on the definition of the program
being exactly that,
like the structure of what like the
program is the medical application of
this thing, right?
We're not trying to take the thing away.
All of the decrem efforts like this
should support that hopefully, you know,
but when people enter the program like it
is the pipeline of like the full healing
model.
So you enter,
you do your onboarding instruments,
you kind of like say,
say there there's like a software model
that like allows you to like construct
your identity in the program and then
select the people or the practitioners
involved in facilitating that experience.
And this pipeline covers months and years
like we have instruments in here,
especially for some of the more edge case
conditions that span up to five years.
So that makes it very,
very different than going to the park
with your friends or on Bicycle Day,
which is coming up.
Everyone can remember Bicycle Day and
celebrate that in whatever way you choose.
But it's like the medical pathway is a
very specific way to interact with this
medicine.
So yeah, I don't know, just thoughts.
Great.
Thank you, Greg.
And anybody else have any public comment
to me?
Dominic just dropped in a couple of
things into the chat.
If you did have a public comment,
please raise your hand.
There's the information about all the
next committee meetings and the board
meetings.
Also how to submit public comments for
the program and then how to submit any
kind of documents, sources,
websites as well.
The documents are there,
the comments and everything for that.
And if you want to provide public comment
regarding the proposed rule,
there is a very specific e-mail address
and very specific postal address to send
that to.
Also the notice of public hearing in the
full text can be seen at the website
provided.
And also because this topic is being
raised about things in a in a DoH do from
an education standpoint.
Here's a link to the materials that the
Center has for cannabis.
We anticipate developing similar
education programs as medical psilocybin
program develops to suck.
Great job everyone.
Everything moves along.
Seems like again,
we've still got about 7 minutes left in
case anybody did want to share any public
comment,
and you can even drop it in the chat if
you need to.
And I'm not seeing anything so of course
I don't like to just say, OK, well,
that's the end event.
So everybody have a great day.
But respecting your time.
If there is any public comment,
please share.
If not, please,
I really hope you have a wonderful rest
of your Friday and great rest of the next
week.
And I'll see you again on May 8th.
Don't forget there is Brenda's meeting
coming up here and it sounds like it's
going to be a great one to be there.
So please.
Eileen says, I just want to say thanks.
My inbox blew up great.
That's exactly what we wanted.
We this is this is where everybody gets
to work together.
So thank you all very much.
Thank you.
Absolutely appreciate y'all's time here
today and we'll see you back on May 8th.
And thank you very much for working
groups.
You guys are awesome.
I can't thank you enough for that.
Thank you everybody.
Have a great weekend.